Hi!
As well as the boiled water technique works for cleaning out baked on gunk from the top, sides, and even bottom of your microwave, water alone is not going to help if you have some slick butter or grease that's been spilled inside that microwave.
For that, we're going to need something to cut the grease.
This will take soap of some sort.
I'm going to use an organic all-purpose cleaner.
You do not want to spray it in your microwave.
You've got vents all over the sides and the top, which can easily get cleaner in them and that's going to potentially mess up your microwave down the line.
Just spray it right on your sponge, and then you're going to use that to wipe up that grease.
It should take it off in a wipe or 2.
Of course, it's very difficult to tell, so you're going to use the test.
Right there it's still a little bit greasy, but you can hear on the side over here.
We've got all that grease up.
It might also be a problem on the glass inside of your microwave oven, so you want to probably use some all-purpose cleaner on the inside of that to keep it clean and streak free.